[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
hey and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast where a majority of the episodes
i'd like to give
a little bit of quick recommendations to
the listeners
right before the episode begins so
today's recommendation is in the form of
someone to follow on youtube
a youtube channel his name is
richard granin his youtube channel is
richard granin
philosophy uh it's just richard and then
g-r-a-n-n-o
philosophy i stumbled upon him uh i like
came upon one of his videos
and he's talking about uh like complex
ptsd
and so i just started listening to him
he kind of just like sits on his couch
or sits in front of like a
white board or you just try to to
explain these concepts and what he's
learned uh
getting through ptsd is uh he's got
advice on drugs and addiction
uh he's got advice on looks like
sexuality guided meditation uh
forgiveness just a lot of great stuff so
that's
richard graham philosophy on youtube
remember this is just something i'm
sharing to you it's free man you could
do this you
if you're ready to handle these things
and you're ready to to go
you know take care of yourself if you're
at this step where you got some stuff
that you know you want to
try to get get a hold of you know you
can do it you can start just tiptoeing
into it and learning about it you don't
have to go full bore you have to buy a
course
any of that just go on youtube and maybe
learn about it like listen for 10
minutes
once a week and then maybe you know in a
few weeks you can listen for 20 minutes
if it really catches your ear
so you're capable man let's get going to
the podcast we got jace let's roll
dude do you know you have like a podcast
voice
i have a podcast voice i think you do oh
[__] yeah i think you kind of have that
that welcome to the late late show you
know i actually uh i was talking with
my last podcast i had with joseph crum
um we were talking about how
he uh when he was younger like how he
got into singing
he loved doing like he was funny guy he
like doing impersonations and stuff like
you know like you make your voice deeper
like like uh garth brooks or something
yeah um and i actually always loved
doing that like that was just super fun
thing for me to do
and um acting like i loved acting too
and i feel like like i don't like
actively participate in these things now
uh-huh but i feel like i do just
naturally have like
i've probably heard enough podcasts i
actively listened to podcasts and while
he's like
the the show host like the ellen
degeneres role is always fascinating and
wonderful when you study that so yeah
i feel like maybe i accidentally like or
subconsciously rather body it
yeah yeah yeah you probably do i'm just
i'm taking notes with alan degeneres i
love podcasts too i've always i mean
i've watched
do you watch the breakfast club yes yeah
sure every one of them
i mean love the breakfast club big fan
of that
but uh joe rogan also a great one too
but
they're just you can actually get on
there and learn yeah bro isn't that
crazy i mean that's
that's the thing about podcasting in
general like even if it's just
not every podcast is educational but i
feel like it's such a way to learn
so many people are brought to podcasting
because they want to learn something
about you know something they're already
interested in exactly and it makes it
enjoyable
and you get to go through that process
of the growth in the same swing
you know and a lot of the times it might
not even be growth but it's like
okay maybe this guy got on the podcast
and act how i don't want to act on the
podcast
because i saw the reaction you know it
evoked
but then i see kanye get on and i'm like
[__]
i wish like at some point that i could
be
in such a solidified spot in my life to
where i can come and speak my mind like
that
you know and not be worried about what
is
susan jake and chris gonna think if i
pop off on this podcast
like this you know like that is so it's
so hard to to grow
out of that it's so hard to like we're
always
we're always strangling like ourselves
like trying like trying to filter
ourselves to make sure we don't say the
wrong thing
um dude we're like we're under there
just trying to breathe we're trying to
figure out what we really want to say
but we're like i don't want to
offend anybody because like that's the
thing man i think
we just got to trust each other that
like you know none of us are purpose
perfect we're not going to always say
the right words we're gonna like flip
over
our sentences and stuff but like if it's
all love it's all love
like it's like i'm not coming from a bad
place like if i said something wrong we
could talk about it and i didn't mean it
probably but exactly and it's like jake
you can say anything that you want and i
don't have to agree with you but i still
love you no doubt
you know what i mean like it doesn't
have to be this
boom boom we're gonna butt heads and you
know have a brawl over and that's what i
love and i am a very opinionated person
i've gotten a lot better with it in the
past
but i love what you said before about
like
we're trying to breathe because that's
how i feel sometimes and you know how
when you're around somebody
and like me you don't know my background
too much but you know when you're around
somebody
and you do know their background so you
literally will say
[__] to to like fit into
what you think that they think is the
right thing yes bro that's so real and
it's funny you do the [__] out of that
yeah and it's just weird because it's
like at the end of the day
we shouldn't have to do that but we've
been kind of conditioned you know
yeah we have been conditioned i mean
it's it's like this like i mean even
from a young age like in the western
world
is i guess the whole world probably but
like you grow up it's like you start
acting out you start being loud in a
position where like your parents are
trying to keep everything quiet and it's
like a
stop no shh like you should shush like
it starts there like this
um and that's not even just a bad thing
that's just like how we have to live in
the world but yeah
it adds up in in so many situations
where
or like people policing like i you know
i have my my cases of people pleasing
hardcore i'm just trying to
all back up so my my when i'm like
projecting where i'm going like okay
like maybe they're into this so let's
talk about that thing
like you know you're saying like uh you
know some of their past like so you can
bring up that and have that relation
with them we're always looking for like
ways and same grounds to have relation
on
and so it could be a bad thing because
we could treat somebody as
we think their past is or we could
make it a good thing and like maybe
start there if there's nowhere else to
start i guess
yeah and then address it like and it
that's a great point because you you can
find common ground
so even though you have differences
you're coming from a point of connection
versus a point of
arguing or conflict right you know and i
feel like if we base things
off that love then it gives us an
opportunity to step
into a different type of realm versus
i'm gonna attack you and you're gonna
attack me and we're gonna see who
thinks my opinion's right and if more
people think mine is right than you then
i'm right
right that's a crazy way to act and we
get caught up in that [__] i mean
the craziness that's going on in the
world there's a lot of that you see like
on social media
you know especially in our small town a
lot of people are just they're so caught
in the nets they're so caught in their
own mazes and the mazes were laying out
for each other on accident without
knowing it
yeah it's it's a mess and i appreciate
that you see
eye to eye and you reach you reach for
conversations and you see new people and
people with
with love first man i think that's a
great thing that's powerful it is
and i think it's important too for
people to understand that like
you don't always have to be feeling that
way
in order to like go into that you know
like you can have a negative feeling
inside you and still go into something
in a positive manner
right yeah you can see that you got that
negative feeling like okay maybe i have
a bias towards this thing
or this person that i'm approaching like
let's not meet there then
yeah like let's start somewhere else i
don't know how it was for you when you
were younger like were you the type to
like spaz on somebody
if they had a different opinion um
no i was never really spa i wouldn't
really spaz i would like backpedal and
then i would
i would backpedal and not stand up for
myself but then i would kind of look at
what's going on okay and then i would
see how i can try to approach it again
so mine was always
like a like i'm right behind someone's
dance
and i'll see if i can okay well now that
i understand you a little bit better
let's see if i can outsmart you almost
so mine wouldn't be like a
pop off but i would try to like almost
get back at them and make sure they know
that
so you had some tactical you had some
tactical
approach that's good in every way you're
an innovator so i feel like that's
something that comes along with that is
finding the right way to approach things
yeah i mean that's my my growing up was
like
like teaching myself these sort of
things is literally just
watching other people like everything
that i know the way that i internalize
things like as an infj to
uh myers-briggs like i
i'm always watching people before i
approach the situation it's like a it's
a
i'm always trying to find where to meet
people at like i'm always trying to find
that common ground and it's not even
like this thing where it's like i'm so
a peaceful i can find you yeah yeah i
don't even it's just what my brain is
naturally doing it yeah it's what my
brain does and i have to navigate the
world like that it's not it's not easy
like
everybody has their thing and the way
they process the world that's just how i
process mine
exactly what did you so so you said
what was your upbringing like like what
was your brain type like back then
so just give you a little background uh
my
mom was the one who raised us my dad was
around but he was never like in the
household i grew up with three other
women
so it was my little sister my big sister
taylor you know
and my mom so uh it was
crazy man it was crazy my mom's in
recovery now but addiction throughout my
whole family you know my mom's been
married five times so
a lot of different people in the
household and stuff like that but uh
i don't know i always felt like my mom
really showed me how to be
self-sufficient
okay you know so she gave me that kind
of boldness i remember we were talking
earlier just about like being in a
household and you know sometimes they're
like be quiet or you're supposed to do
this or
have your manners at the dinner table
like i didn't grow up eating dinner at
the table
you know all right but i listened to my
mom
be very bold and that gave
me permission subconsciously to do the
same thing with people around me
right yeah so it was something that i'm
really grateful for
and like a lot of people can look at
certain situations and you know take one
thing from it but i'm super happy like
we didn't you know have the biggest
house and [__] like that but like my mom
taught me to fish and now i can eat
forever you know like oh yeah
so it's it's dope and i always try to
look at the positive side of it you know
i know a lot of people can get like
resentments towards their parents and
stuff which is a total natural feeling
you know
walking into school and maybe you don't
have the right outfit on and somebody
talks some [__] to you and then you're
like well [__] dad if you were here and
you would have gave me [__] then no
doubt i'd be fresh and i'd be in the
circle with the cool people instead of
over here looking at a certain dad you
did this to me by not buying me that
jacket that i said i needed
yeah as a young kid we will formulate
our entire like
existence off these things if we're not
careful we will yeah we will and it's
it's a very very scary territory
it is to make that your ultimatum
right bro but it's you know i think a
lot i think we stumble into it a lot
like
um a lot of people our age year old say
between 20 and 30 i feel like nowadays
are just
you know childhood trauma like that's a
huge thing that we're like working
through and a lot of it is like
like for me it points to
where i was doing stuff like that like i
would see like all the resentments that
i would have towards my mom
and it's like well you know you justify
them in such
strange ways as a teenager and um
and like even if you you get to a point
where you accept them and you're like
okay i do feel these things like
here's what's going on then you kind of
have to look at like okay i was like
acting out
because of that i was i was changing the
way that i would interact with this
person because i
am mad that they weren't this thing for
me at this age and i've kept that going
for seven years you know what i mean
exactly you get to a point where you're
older with the parent stuff where it's
like
you've got to really start seeing them
as just a separate that they're a human
being living their life and you're a
human being living their life
you took the words right out of my mouth
man that is the best
way to put it they're a human yeah hey
it's hard as heck i mean i have
i've got i talk about my counselor like
i struggle with a lot of family stuff
still
yeah um but it's it's it's where you
gotta be you gotta just try to remind
yourself like
i'm getting mad at them i'm expecting
them i'm wishing they were doing these
things for me at this moment but
i'm not inside their brain i can't be
yeah no and like
just like we go through things that
shape us to be the people we are like
we weren't there when our moms and dads
were growing up no
man they could be repeating the same
cycles that they went through
you know and like we're lucky enough
jake that we have an opportunity to
where we live in a time where you can go
on this phone right here and you can get
so much
positive information along with negative
information you'll be the you be the
you know dictator on which direction
you're going to go but
it's it's incredible yes it's nothing
short of incredible
yeah it's it's a it's a lot for us to
like deal with but it's so great that we
we can deal with it and we can learn
from it and grow i mean dude our
this generation like of people who are
just absorbing all this you know
the childhood trauma stuff like that
whole corner of the internet it's gonna
be beautiful in like four to five here
it's like in crazy ways like we're gonna
understand each other on such
intellectual levels it's gonna be great
it already has i mean just
think about like the conversation of
anxiety 20 years ago
right they would people would walk away
they wouldn't even like let you finish
talking they'd like i don't even know
you're not even speaking english be like
dude
you're a [__] get over yeah like what
so
so you're sad [__] man up bro exactly
when it's like a lot
when it's like that is such a real thing
and i have a friend who
actually is going through like severe
almost to like a disassociation point of
anxiety right now
so it's like really been heavy on my
heart and i can tell when i talk to him
that like
i've never felt anything like that and
so that makes me really feel for him
and it makes me like understand that
we can't be so judgmental right off the
rip because
we don't know what other people are
feeling right
what do you so that part you're talking
about
how you like because you felt your own
pain like you felt the human emotions
like you but you're like
i haven't felt this like what you're
particularly feeling like you are able
to recognize
like what you're going through is
something that i haven't had to deal
with but i can i can empathize with
like i'm feeling that you can recognize
that i think so many people
it's not an easy thing to do at all but
like being able to recognize that
is a powerful position a lot of times
we're always trying to understand like
from experience like
um as much as i'm always trying to draw
in my life
like how can i relate to this person
with what i've been through a lot of
times it's like dude i didn't even
i can't even imagine what you're going
through but like
that typical thing of letting yourself
slip into their shoes
you know like put yourself in their
shoes it really is so powerful so
powerful
and you could do that for a second like
you did like hey man i feel this and
like it's something
it's it's next level yeah but it's real
and and so what what do you just as a
homie
um say we've got say we've got a
listener
that they've got homies who the listener
doesn't deal with too much anxiety
themselves but they've got homies who do
okay i always want to give give a little
bit of like here's something maybe you
could say this maybe you could
give them this example maybe you could
be this sort of pillar for them
um same situation what do you got advice
i love that i love that and
so my biggest thing in situations like
this is
number one over anything i have to be
there right so i have to validate these
feelings because i know that if my
friend is telling me something then it
must be what he's actually feeling
and so after i validate that for them it
kind of takes some of the power away
from
it you know because i'm i'm i'm
revalidating to him that it's
okay that you're feeling like this and
not only am i saying that i'm saying i
don't feel like this but i still think
it's okay for you to feel like this
you know and then number two it's i
really gotta be there so not just over
text like when this happened a week ago
it was with my really close friend and
me and jc hopped in the car
and we went and picked him up and we
went to portland and there was nobody
there because like the code and stuff
and it was just cool and you can see
like people slowly start to transform
outside of their feelings
when they have other positive humans
around them
whether they're still feeling the
emotion or not it
makes them feel like okay i have support
yes you know because when you're by
yourself especially like you can really
convince yourself in your own head
cavity of like
this is the absolute truth this is what
i am i am this thought i am this
wrangler of this thought
yes you know yeah like and what you
pulled him right out of it but i like
how he said validate
validating his feelings so i think that
that's a hard one um
i always have to remember with myself
because i'm such like an advice giver
i'm like bro i got the answer like
because
i i have certain relationships with
certain friends that like it's been that
for so long
that it is like they're coming to me for
that yep and there's that but there's
also times where i'll get too carried
away and i got to slow down myself and
be like hey
say are you okay like hey i love you
listen everything's gonna be okay make
sure you don't forget to say like
this really i get that like explain
further like
let them get it out um address that like
hey man
this sucks i'm so sorry like not just
run write it sometimes i'll run right
into like here's what you've got to do
bro
what did you meditate yes yes yes that's
me
i never want to like push people [__]
like that no no and i
always too because i'm about if i have a
problem
i'm about a solution that's how i am
okay and so
it always puts you you are just
conditioned
if somebody comes to you with the
problem to say okay how are we going to
figure this out
which is such a great quality in a human
being right right
like you're not just going to sit on the
couch and go oh i'm [__]
you know you know what i mean like there
ain't no way i'm getting out of this
stuck here forever yeah because the
thing is some people do that [__] yeah
let's keep it real some people do that
[__] you know and and we don't know what
they're going through whatever but i
know it ain't gonna work
yeah yeah i know you're gonna feel the
same way the next day you know and so
for me i do that too but a lot of the
times even with my text and [__] now
jake like
i'll write a response and i'll be like
oh
that's too preachy oh yeah i'm i'm
always doing that
yeah you know so but i'll still say what
i wanted to say
but like you were talking about before
with approach i'll still say what i'm
gonna say
but i start my conversation differently
and then i bring it in as like the
closer
right right you know because dude i mean
that's we got to remember like we know
our in the people who are contacting us
about this stuff like we're close to
them a lot of times we know them it's
like hey
remember like they're they're sensitive
just like you and you know
you know specifically like if it's your
good homie like i know how he's
sensitive
so i'm going to make sure i don't poke
that button i'm not going to prod that
bull on my homie like
because you know i just as a human
myself i got places where it's like you
poke me there and i'm like
you know yeah everybody's got that too
me too when you know that you're homie
or your family member or someone you
love
listener is in that spot starting with
that like
that validation is so great yes that's
great advice
um i want to so talking about upbringing
i was it's been floating in my head and
i got i could be freaking wrong but did
you grow up
in south kelso um in hud housing yes
yeah bro i i lived right by you so yeah
yeah so i got a vic
my family got evicted from those like
the yellow duplexes
on the 9th okay okay yeah you know i
think i just remember because i think i
remember like your sister was always
around like i don't think we were
friends
but i like knew who she was or something
like that of course of course
yeah yeah i can't remember like i'm too
maybe we played hide and seek together
probably
yeah we were probably out there doing
some finessing in the neighborhood
yeah it's crazy uh it's it's so i mean
obviously it seems like another lifetime
ago but it seems like someone else's
life when you think about like childhood
like the older i get the more i'm like
man that was like my life was just so
different like
you get back you get disconnected from
it
you know especially because a guy like
yourself you
take the bull by the horns and you make
your situation look different
right you know and once you make your
situation look different it's very easy
for you to forget
where you came from right you know and
that is such a good thing to make your
situation look different but i always
like to like you just said you had that
thought
think back to that moment because that's
a way i can pull gratitude into today
yes you know is like i'm so grateful
that
um my whole family has put themselves in
the position to not
be there anymore you know and like you
get the opportunity to show people that
even though that's where you came from
that you don't have to stay there
right you know yeah that's cool yeah
thanks for pointing that out too i think
it's uh
a big thing with me is like making sure
i'm not bringing resentment with me too
like i have a lot of like
you know i gotta work through it and
that's a big thing that i'm trying to do
is like you know i'm working through my
[__] out loud like i don't
wanna got [__] figured out man i'm
trying to figure it out though because i
think that
that their strength in just telling
people like let's fail together let's do
it out loud let's
you know let's try there is there is and
i love that point because for so long
i thought i had it all figured out man
thought i had it all figured out
and it's crazy to think about the times
where i thought i had it all figured out
in my life when i look at him now i'm
like man you were real
you were tripping knucklehead bro yeah
you're you're really tripping tell me
you know and it's just like now you get
to and i love what you said because when
you stay
green and you you reaffirm that you have
more to learn and more to become that's
exactly what happens
yeah you know every day is something new
to learn man
yeah every conversation everybody knows
something you don't and that's the
truest thing ever like that is
the most true you can't even like argue
with it for a second second everybody
knows something you don't
everybody and even if they don't let's
say it's like everybody does and it's
like you can look at somebody say okay
that's what i'm not gonna do
right yeah you know it's something to
learn from him something to learn from
you know what i mean so it's like to
have that perspective i think
is worth more than anything
no doubt uh let's talk about perspective
man i feel like you got a great
perspective and i'm excited that you are
newly hopping into the the writing game
yes
and by writing i mean i mean hip hop rap
man you've been starting making music
lately
i think that's so great um i you know
i see things so i had a comedian on
um uh joseph krum great guy
and i like i was i kept calling him or
like referring to him when i was typing
it back up as a funny philosopher
um and i've i'm really obsessed with
philosophy the last couple years like
learning it in my own way um exploring
what it means exploring like with comedy
is kind of like pointing out the edges
of the stuff
like we got to make fun of ourselves so
we know what our edges are and where we
can push them
and know that we're being ridiculous um
philosophers you know
are always like hey here's how reality
is and here's how we're going to mess it
up if we're not dumb
and you add historians here's what
happened before and whatever
but i you know if you look at like what
future
what our future like or current time has
done
to me it's this like incredible just big
old bowl
mixed of like cultures in um like
there's not just a
philosopher now and not just a poet but
there's there's like
music makers who are trying to
communicate those same things
that that philosophers and poets
and writers and stuff are always trying
to communicate you're pulling something
from your brain that's not here in
physical reality
you're trying to write it down you're
trying to say it over some lyrics um
you're trying to create a feeling out of
nothing right exactly and
it's almost like channeling yes you know
and okay channeling bro uh for a
listener who has no idea what you're
talking about you're getting a low
download okay so and i'll just
i'll i'll be real real brutally honest
with you guys too so a year and a half
ago if you would have told me something
about channeling i would have looked at
you like you were crazy
okay um luckily i have an amazing woman
who has came into my life
since that point and who has put me onto
spirituality and channeling and things
like that
and so like on mother's day for example
okay
i had nothing planned jake nothing
planned at all i'm driving okay we're in
a red leaf drive-through
and all of a sudden i get this
overwhelming feeling
to write something and so i pull out my
iphone i pull out my notes
and i start writing this poem for my mom
now when i'm doing that
it doesn't feel like i'm consciously
doing it it feels like it's
very natural and easy and to me that's
what channeling
is it's when you are very connected with
real raw feelings
and so the stuff that's go i feel like
martin luther king was probably
channeling
you know like he had such a strong
feeling inside of him in such beliefs
that it
allowed him to go in front of people and
let that overcome him and that's why
people were like well
and i've noticed that when i create
outside of channeling
it's a lot different what do you mean
create outside of channeling like with
other people where it's not like your
creativity
no i mean i feel like i create in
different states
okay and i appreciate each state that i
create in but
there's these moments where i'm like
this is it
you know yes and i can be around people
for sure you know it's definitely not i
have to be alone
but it's like it's that feeling when you
think you got one
it's like when you're in the studio and
you're like and everybody's like this
that's it yes that's six that's the one
that's the single we're putting out
before that
because it's gonna go bro you gotta get
yourself there even if it's not you
gotta say that it is like you've got
yes like like if nobody ever believed in
themself like literally think about it
if nobody ever believed in themselves
what would our life be like
like who is the the people who are
supposed to believe in themselves the
ones who are supposed to change
things and supposed to write incredible
things and just make music
right like they got to believe in
themselves and that's why i love
russ ross bro i love i love russ and the
whole rap community takes a big [__] on
him
it's funny i think that's a ploy bro
that's a weird thing oh
you know you know what it is it's
insecurity because he represents
everything that they don't
for sure you know and that's why they
attacked that man and
guess what does he say it in the most
humble way
of course not it's hip-hop it's hip-hop
it literally hip-hop was created on
standing in front of somebody and
telling them everything
that you are better at and everything
that's wrong with them
and pulling all their demons up that's
what it's built off of it's a sport
we're sparring
yeah and we're gonna see who's better
you know and so like i love that i love
that stick your chest out
type of [__] you know and i feel like
that not only in
music has made me what you know what i'm
going for but like
in everything in my career with sales
and everything like
waking up and saying you got this you
got to you know
there's so much in this world that's
trying to tell you the exact opposite
every day bro
exactly exactly and you know what i
believed it sometimes
yeah and you know you know what helps me
really believe that i can win
is staying disciplined yeah discipline
equals freedom that's what jocko willing
says
discipline equals freedom and you know
what most people think
the opposite yeah you know you ain't
really free
just because you don't got any
obligations the more obligations i have
during the day the better i feel about
myself the more i think i can win
period yeah bro
you gotta it's just like i wrote that
don't strangle it
on the sticky note here like that's how
it is it's it's funny because you think
of
discipline and you think that that's
strangling it but it's like you already
know what you want
the discipline is how do you get what
you know you want
yes something like that yes exactly like
that exactly
and then you have a plan of action
yeah you know like you turn the dream
into a goal exactly
and you lay out this see for me i feel
really
like and for the viewers too um
like maybe you don't like to wake up in
the morning right like when you wake up
maybe that's when like you're feeling
the most depressed and
you kind of take a while to you know
come to life and start feeling positive
and getting those endorphins going and
stuff like that like
try try before you go to sleep
have your exact day mapped okay like
have your exact day i know when i do
that and i wake up the next day
it's like i feel more excited because i
know what's going on like this morning i
got to wake up and get on my bike and
exercise
and then get some fruit in me and then i
knew i was coming here to do this
podcast
and just so everybody everybody
listening like
of course the first thing i think is i
haven't seen jake in a long time
probably going to be some anxiety before
i go there right yeah you know what it's
going to take us a few minutes to get
the ball rolling and connect
like who knows who's there who knows
what kind of mood he's gonna be in
you know what i mean who knows who knows
if we're gonna buy and i'm a
perfectionist man so it's like
i want it to go perfect i want to say
all the right [__] well you want to show
up prepared but you're also showing up
for something that's like
it's you know a conversation it's not
like an
interview it's a conversation like let's
see where we go from what we relate on
you know not so much something you could
super prepare for
exactly exactly and that's the beautiful
part about things like this
yeah you know is they but the the point
of that
is to is to commit i knew once i sent
you that dm
and you said yes i'm coming it's on i'm
coming
you know so like but the hard part isn't
coming it's sending the dm in the first
place and committing
right you know dude it's huge and it
seems so overly obvious but there's so
many like
there's so many weights lifted off our
chest that it would just be just send
that dm bro like if you want to work
with that rapper and you think your
beats are tight
send them the [__] man like what could
happen send it like he says no like
all right well where were you before
yeah same place
maybe he reads it and doesn't respond at
least you know you tried
yeah and then you know what that's going
to build a muscle to where the next time
you try to
in one time they're going to respond
right
we're dude we're and i say we're with a
hardcore
mirror right in my face finger right at
my soul like
we're so afraid of failing you know i
try my hardest like i try to
you know i try to wear my heart on my
sleeve where i can i try to
try to fail out loud like i tried
especially with my music and stuff like
because music is i've been djing for a
long time but music production and like
singing and playing piano like i love it
but i know that i'm not super good at it
so i really try to fail out loud and
like i'll even post it on social media
because
i think that there's nowhere in this
world we're so we see
everything through the eyes of our media
now that we don't see failure anymore
bro we just see
amazing people we see six-year-olds who
are just playing a harmonica and a
keyboard with their toes and you're like
[__]
what can i do man so we don't even try
bro so we don't even try we don't even
we not only try like don't get a try
because we're like there's a part of us
we're like i can do this i really want
to do this i want to go all in like i
want to
really try to be a musician i really
want to try to be a rapper i really want
to try to be a
whatever there's that so we get crippled
to not even do that but we also get
crippled to just create
and creativity is something that all
humans should be able to partake in
you should be able to sing and [__] up
you should be able to play piano
and hit wrong notes like you know you're
not the one who's going to be on stage
performing for hundreds of people
anytime soon
but like it's for you it's enjoyable yes
and you love it
you know and that's what and that's what
it boils back to is that
but you're so right and we get crippled
by the thought of dealing or
you post that picture and it don't get
enough likes and then six hours later
you're like oh i'm [__] taking that
[__] down and then when you take it down
you're like who's gonna see that it
didn't get enough likes and i took
it down bro that is some weird [__] that
we put ourselves through
i mean i mean it's crazy and you know
i'm speaking from my own
my own stuff you know but it's we get so
obsessed
with somebody else reassuring us that
what we're doing is what we're supposed
to be doing instead of
trusting our intuition right we're
pretty we're pretty disconnected from
our intuition
yes do you think do you think in order
to get more in tune with our intuition
we need to be willing to fail
i do i do i think that we need to be
willing to take a hard look at what the
world's trying to tell us
right because i feel like everybody has
a gift
and i feel like some people's gift is to
be a nurse
and help people and some people's gift
is to be an amazing teacher
you know i know for me with music i
always knew it was it for me
always ever since i can remember just
i love it when i hear music when i write
when i rap in front of people
it's what makes me feel alive see now i
denied that
for so long because of fear of failure
so it caused me to cover up those bad
emotions
because i knew what i was supposed to be
doing and i wasn't doing it
so i was feeling such bad emotions that
i'm like okay well i'm gonna drown
myself in this substance so i don't have
to
you know what i mean so i don't have to
look at
the hard facts in the mirror which is
you are being called to do something
and you are not doing it right it's
magical man i think it's beautiful i
think we're
we all got something that we could like
man every single listener wherever
you're at in your car
headphones wherever it's at like there's
something inside of you that you know
exactly what it is for you bro like it's
yeah even if it's it's garyvee said this
thing one time i was like that's so real
he's like
if making smurf shirts is is
something you love doing more than
anything you love printing smurfs faces
on shirts and selling them
and it's your passion you just love
smurfs and you think they're and it's
this your thing
that is your you love it so much like
what are you doing not doing it damn it
like what are you doing and i love me
some gary vee man yeah
great great great perspective and that's
so
true it's so true and it's so hard
sometimes because people are like
god a smurf shirt that's a dumb idea
even though i love to do it
you know you know someone's writing it
down you know but then once they act and
once they actually swallow the pride and
they you know
start making them and they realize that
maybe
susie likes smurf shirts too that's
the that's the revelation that's the
point where you're like okay
this is it and this is where even bigger
than that comes in
maybe everyone hates them but you love
them right so keep going
exactly keep going see that's the thing
is we think that we're all trying to get
there's like this one
they right there's this one like i got
to make something and it's got to meet
this standard like if you're making
music you're making hip hop it's got to
be able to go right head to head with
with little wayne and biggie and like
all the it's like what like
i'm not trying to insert the thing i'm
making to be competition
with with other things i think that that
cripples us sometimes the
um being afraid to fail a lot of times
is a lot of times because we're
we're at the starting line of the wrong
race like we started with the wrong why
like like we think uh
here's a good example um i had a guy
that was
an electrician that was like doing
something here and uh me and me and
homie were here and we were working on
some stuff and he came in and he was
just being polite he's a
really nice maintenance guy but uh his
natural thing to say
i don't hear a lot when i work at
warehouser is like um oh man one one big
hit that's all it takes is one big hit
and like i would always hear that and
then he said that and i it made it click
like
oh he thinks that like getting famous is
the end goal here
he thinks that like getting to that
level of like
like what i'm doing is to get to that
and that is a symptom of what you're
doing that is if you get to that fame
and people worship you and people listen
to your music
to me that's like you know in making
deals and making money off of your [__]
yes that is a symptom of just putting
your head down and like doing what only
you can do so well
yes right and and i think a lot of times
we start at that finish line
and we but you know back to failure we
failed the race because we're we're
at the wrong terminal we're not even at
the right place we're about to race
we're about to race the 400 and we want
to do a long distance man
yeah yeah so i i think just start
starting with your why man like that i
think i mentioned another podcast
start with why by simon sinek that book
you probably read that i love it and i
have read it and simon sinek he's next
level man yeah he is next so i love his
perspective on stuff but the fact that
you were in a place jake to even
hear that and dissect that that's not
where you're going for
because i feel like we were talking
about media before it's like
we are we see the billboards that's what
people
glamorize right or the car or
you know the perfect looking person who
behind closed doors isn't so perfect and
so
those are the things that we go for and
we forget that
most of the time the people that are on
the billboards
they're coming from a true genuine state
of creativity
and that's just a product of it yeah you
know
we like them because they're able to be
so original like that's what we want
yeah we want to be that within ourselves
and i feel like the whole world it's all
just feeling
right it's feeling so like when you hear
that record like when you hear that
record
and you're like yep you know like you
feel you feel you know or like when you
have a really good friendship
you know like you just feel it yeah you
know and so like
i'm trying to feel more instead of
look for my gratification
in other things right i feel that
because it's so
temporary yeah in things it's so
temporary like and it gets less and less
as you keep going like at least for me
i always know growing up i was like okay
i want this and then once you get it and
you still
feel the hole you're like oh [__] oh
yeah
it's like right away too like oh yeah
that hole's there yeah it's like right
away
try to keep doing that thing you just
keep falling just keep keep chasing that
carrot on a stick
without ever asking yourself what
character you're chasing yeah exactly
and then it's like and then it's like
for what and you talk about the they and
that's what it's for is for they
and we're supposed to do stuff for us
yeah you know yeah
and like truly be able to
because guess what if your intention is
to make
somebody else feel less than by what you
have
like i know personally how that feels
and like it's just the wrong move
it's the wrong move like it's the wrong
move
not for them for you because at the end
of the day i know
my whole goal and everything
and you know i feel that with you too is
like
i just want to be happy yeah you know
yeah i'm just trying to live this life
man yeah
i just want to say that i did that i
really tried to do it at least you know
like i want to say that i
put my head down and like explored this
life and i experienced what i really
wanted to experience
i'm so glad you just said that too
because when i
put the first song on my soundcloud
you know what my thought was because i
had been thinking it
for years and i feel like this
subconscious thought led me to so much
bad in my life is
what if i die and nobody knows i ever
wanted to make music or this is what i
am
and so when that first song came out
it's like nothing matters after this
i don't have to make one more song i
have to make one more song people know
this is what i wanted and this was me
and whether
i have some vulgar [__] in there because
that's what i experienced or that's what
i grew up
looking up to and thought was cool that
was your life it's me
yeah it's me and you can like it or hate
it
i love you yeah bro you know what i mean
like i love you you listen
i'm grateful for that and even if you
don't listen you hear people saying that
that's what i'm doing like you know what
i mean so it's like
that's that's where the that's where the
hot spot is for me you know like yeah
that's that's
important man we get caught up with i
feel like i come to places with my music
and my like creation my sound art and
poetry and stuff that i like
like i'm not trying to make something
that people will like
which is you know with music you get
that's a slippery slope because you
can't be dumb and ignore the audience
like i get that yes but i'm also
who i am what i'm trying to be is you
know in my heart i feel like i'm
i'm a revolutionary like in my heart i i
want to
push the edges of music i want to make
new kinds of music i want to i want to
i want i want people to
make edits of my music and make it
better like maybe
maybe they remix the idea that i had
because maybe they're like
he lacked it on this and i want to make
sure it makes sense or something like i
like i'm not doing it to to be liked i
want to do
what what means the most to me what
means the most to me is like creativity
and like trying to push the edges of it
not trying to get it right
yeah the juices i hear that with you a
lot and
you know it's brought me a great amount
of perspective because
i'm so the opposite yeah like when i
hear you like when we were
over here before we started the podcast
and you're like you know and you can
just fail and mess with it like when i
go in i'm like [__] i need something
that's gonna [__] work
you know what i mean and then like it
kind of takes you because
here's where my mind goes is you know
drake made twosie slide for tick-tock
right you know what i mean so like you
see things like that
and it puts you in that room but it's
like i also want to stay true to me
and i know when i'm doing things out of
that reverse engineer state
although they might be what's popped it
kind of takes you away
from the straight line that you're
supposed to go
in your true purpose you know but i
really love what you said also before we
got on the podcast is
you could never explain yourself in one
three minute and 30 second song no
matter how hard you try much as we think
we can
we're like yeah this represents me it's
like dude people haven't figured out
they don't have you figured out now bro
right yeah
yeah and it's different because there
will be times where i go into
making music and it's it's ego for two
minutes and 40 seconds on
a track right and then there's other
times where it's vulnerability and me
talking about what i really went through
in my life and
shivering from withdrawals and like real
[__] and like
feelings are fickle right you know like
one day you can wake up jake and be like
i'm [__] jake bryan's baby
you know what i mean and then the next
day you can wake up and be like
damn i mean that's how i feel for real
already
yeah yeah you know and so like i see
different spectrums and i want to create
off of all the reality and not
minimize it yeah dude we got to explore
we got to be willing to fail we got to
be willing to like
try out other people's [__] like all
right let's how do i get it to be like
that like oh okay so drake made this for
tick tock like
let me try that out like but don't get
too caught up like if you get in the
booth and you're like just play that
drake instrumental and let me just
freestyle over for fun
that's learning that's great you don't
have to walk out and be like i
represented myself 100
it's like no no i'm put back to my craft
yeah i'm learning it like okay i tried
this style of hip-hop because it's going
to make my
vocal structure better in this way now
my lips know how to move in this
specific way man
give it 20 years of just like trying
[__] and not
not settling for any of it and you're
gonna be and that goes back to what
you're saying about not being scared to
fail
yeah and it's so important and like in
caring what people think too much
right you know because then it really
just halts uh bro this is like at least
you got a great catch on board
i've been eyeing it i'm unplug this real
quick but uh give me the lowdown of
uh give me a little down of your start
with music because i know because i want
to make sure i cover um
your your smart business man too like
you've like i want to make sure we
you've got some info from the books
you've got some info from from real life
experience from being a salesman you've
met a lot of kind of people you're good
at people
um that's that's super great and i love
how you're like you're taking that and
putting it into
a more passionate thing so let's skip
before before
you were a salesman tell me about um
like when you were younger when you
first got into hip hop itself like you
remember what you were listening to
yeah who you were listening to yeah so
like i was the
i was the kid who like fell asleep to uh
eminem
you know you know eight mile everything
like that
uh when 50 cent you know first started
coming out and he had you know in the
club
and all those types of records that just
went
i knew early on that that was something
that i was
overwhelmingly excited about
you know like because when you sit in a
room you know some people like
some people see a fidget spinner and
they're like that's their [__] and then
other people like what the hell is that
thing like
this was you know this was my thing and
so
i just got so indulging in it you know i
just wanted to
hear everything and now that i've grown
old like i love i love asap rocky
no doubt because of his visuals and his
flow like
i love people for i love russ because i
can just see
the genuine human being that he is
and like he gives me a different
perspective when i go to his instagram
page i see him with his mom
yeah you know and like i love that
wholesome you know and then like i go to
future
and i i hear him say you know
you know he's basically pissing on him
yeah he's you know
he's at six other other people's mom
exactly but i love him as an artist like
he he brought me feelings like in
a type of energy and swag that i love
you know and it doesn't mean that i
condone what he does
yeah that's some silly dude we get let's
we gotta get caught up real right here
really quick
so put a pin in where we were at but i
actually had um in this similar sense of
like people thinking i represented
when r kelly like first started getting
like
it was like the case came back up like a
year ago where he was like
he did some [__] up [__] and i was
playing
not even an r kelly song but it was one
of those songs where you'd be like wait
what song is
it is r kelly it's like something it was
like shaggy or something like that like
something that you'd think with
with our kelly and this girl who was
drunk she comes up to me with a finger
in my face like do you know
what what r kelly has done like freaking
out on me but and i'm like
hold up yeah you think that i'm right
like
i didn't pause the mic and say yo this
song i'm about to play
i condone it and piss on your friends
piss on little kids
because that's what this [__]
does like what yeah i know like dude i'm
doing my job i'm playing like
i don't have time to listen to what's
going on in the news right now like i
mean there's certain things you like
just don't play this song in that
certain environment but
exactly we do yeah like you can
love something about someone like future
man future is such a
talented rapper he's so in his own lane
he pushed the boundaries in so many ways
he he gives you that feeling bro lyrics
lyrics and
especially with hip-hop lyrics and a
beat are trying to communicate a feeling
to us anyway bro and future gives us
that feeling it's not so much about
i mean i'm again i don't want to condone
everything that he does myself
but like yeah it's uh
you're so so you always vibe off of like
you're a feeler like you're always like
this makes me feel i want to see what
that's about
like exactly and with music even on my
way over here
like i'm picking my songs in consciously
this isn't subconsciously i'm
consciously thinking what type of mood
do i want to be in when i get out of my
car and say hi to jake
you know what i do say yeah you know so
like for me that's what it does
and the fact that people are able to
bring you that
i have to understand that those people
are people and just because they're
famous does not take away the fact that
they are
constantly making mistakes exactly like
i am right you just
like that's where i get a disconnect i
gotta be honest with somebody because
like for me it's like
just because they have a hundred hits
doesn't mean that they're not going
through the same [__] you are
it doesn't mean cause he's kevin hart
that
he might not end up at a pool party and
sleep with another woman and get [__] on
for it
right you know what i mean like we're as
a human being we're people we're
and guess what do i want to do
everything possible to set myself up to
where that never happens because i love
my woman so much and i do not want to
hurt her of course
yeah but do i learn from kevin hart
exactly yeah dude we get it
when you could just look at things
through the lens of like not trying to
find what you don't like about somebody
but like i think
when music lovers have this thing that a
lot of people
that non-music lovers sometimes don't
get and it's is that like
like i'm not
it's i'm finding what i like about you
like i'm finding what i like
people who are like hip-hop fans and
like oh okay like because
do you like all genres of music like do
you i do yeah so you do
so like just finding i'm not trying to
represent it i'm not trying to say that
this represents what i believe in i'm
just saying like this person made me
feel a certain way and that's amazing
like as human beings on this world
like why aren't we just trying to have
different experiences and different
musicians could give us different
experiences
yeah you're open to them though exactly
exactly you got to be open to it and i
feel like a chance we get so
caught up in our own agenda
that it's hard you know and i totally
understand you know
what people are doing when they're
coming at you in that certain
circumstance
is they're trying to bring you to where
they are
and i did that stuff too with my friends
and stuff you know because you want
you feel validated if people think what
you think and you
get offended when you don't right you
know
but like that's how i know like when i
talk to you
like i know that you are in a process of
growth
no doubt yeah you know and like that's
how try to be upfront about it man
that's what i'm yelling it from the
mountains like yeah i'm
not [__] perfect man by any means and
that and even by
saying that it allows you to have other
people come
into your life right you know like and
what i mean by that is like
some people might have been intimidated
by you you know
always a cool kid in school always was
able to get around
in the social crowd you know and by you
saying that
i'm not this one thing and i'm going
through a process of
enduring all qualities of life and
accepting all different perspectives
gives people the opportunity to say he
isn't he isn't just this one thing even
though that is a part of him
so maybe he'll understand me and where
i'm coming from
and give me an opportunity wonderful
that's a great perspective
i'm glad he pointed that pointed that
out for me too
yeah dude you gotta do just giving
people that open slate
just allowing them to grow allowing them
to
you we we tried to define ourselves in
three minutes and 30 seconds we try to
find ourselves in
one podcast like i'll get new time
podcasts on here and they'll text me
afterwards and be like hey you you can
you can delete whatever like i kind of
rambled whatever and i'm like hey
you're good yeah you are good yeah
you didn't no you didn't represent
exactly who you are and if someone
listened to this and they never met you
in their life they know exactly who you
are no because that's [__] impossible
yes you can i got almost 50 episodes you
don't know who i am
but until you say that to them see by
you being in a spot of growth jake you
are enabling people to feel better about
themselves
because then you get the response you
don't respond like this oh yeah i'm
definitely gonna cut that out it was a
little outlandish and rambling but you
hit him with the response that you say
yeah it's okay and guess what
you got next time yeah that's what i
love i hope i [__] up come on again i
hope this
i hope this track doesn't go the next
one's gonna yeah dude you know what i
mean and then that's
that's that chip on your shoulder and i
love that [__] because i i've been like
back against the wall my whole life so
like that's the attitude i've always had
you know like
i woke up to a dirty [__] alley
growing up before i went to school you
know what i mean so like
that for me that stick your chest out
and
i feel like that has contributed to
where i'm at but now that i
used that to build a solid
backing as far as being taken care of
now guess what it's time to work on
being humble yeah letting other people
have their opinion even though you
disagree
right i got a question for you what
do you think for you started
your process on self-reflecting and
really trying to open yourself up to go
to a next level spiritually in
other ways yeah mine was um i mean long
story short
like suicidal as hell like it was uh
it was like a lot of things compounding
and it was almost
with the suicide thing it was almost
like started to be my personality to me
like i didn't realize
i was i've had this i had a moment
where i literally had put a gun a
physical gun to my head
touched it with my my temple and it was
like there was
no moment where i was like uh
like i wasn't instantly aware like did i
just put a gun to my head what am i
doing what the [__] like it wasn't
grossed out by the gun
i was i like could look at it afterwards
and be like okay so that's
that's exactly how far away it is huh
and it's um
and so in but i didn't have the ability
so that moment wasn't super profound to
me when it happened
it was retrospectively later when i was
like what the [__]
so i was so caught up in who
i had made my identity to be because i
thought i
i needed to be these things or deserve
to be these things
um but so in around that same time
i did have like one night where
like that that train of thought like
woke up of like a what are you doing
like where i needed that i needed that
part of me i needed that spiritual side
of me that person who
who wants love that jake who who who
just wants to live life and be a human
and just
experience love before i die like that
part wasn't
didn't have the reins but it was so like
shoved down in in inside
it was there it was there yeah it was
there but like so in
the gun moment i was down here before i
had like redone anything it was like
just kind of a basement that i would uh
you know like i did my dj work down here
in [__] but yeah yeah
um but i i essentially like
i didn't realize it but i didn't have
that awakening moment of like
what are you doing like put this gun
down get what was it like curiosity
or was it like well so okay so so i had
i had like around that moment i don't
know if this was like within weeks or
whatever but i had
had this other moment where that part of
me did come on it came online
okay um and i was we were out having
drinks
uh it was like probably two years ago
now but i was out with shay um
in like did shea know how you're feeling
so
no so that's the thing is like the way
that i am
i didn't share like i didn't i've in my
eyes in my head i've raised myself since
i was nine years old
that's how my so i am very
i have to do it on my own like i have to
keep it in my head and i mean i'm way
better at this sort of thing now but
right
um yeah dude i had this had this moment
where essentially we were drinking too
much and i felt a little tipsy
um and i got behind the wheel and i
literally grabbed a bag of blow out of
my wallet
and i did a bump like in front of
shaylee and like like she's she's known
that i've done it before like she
lets me live my life whatever yeah for
sure um and i i did it in like it was
like right away it was like this moment
of like
this [__] light that flew into the
car that was like what are you you just
made this normal what are you doing bro
you just you're sobering up with a quick
bump because you had too many drinks so
you could take your girl
and it was like looking at her like what
are you doing you know what i mean and
you love her so that
you know that disappoints you yeah and
so and so i think that was like the
avalanche
um and that was like that was a little
bit before halloween um
in i had like a really bad like
emotional breakdown
um after a halloween show yeah and it
was but it was instead of doing it on my
own which i think that night would have
been like a very
not safe night me versus me sort of
situation
um where i like texted shaylee i called
her like before i left the gig and i was
like you have to stay up please
like stay up and that was something i
didn't have i didn't have that thing
that was
like willing to make the call and be
like a weak man and like
this is how i'm feeling yeah and i was
like you got to stay up because like i'm
not doing good and then essentially like
that night i got home and it was like
i had to leave uh i had to leave for a
show out of town in the morning or
something but i was like
five hours four hours of just like
bawling in the shower of just like
um just being vulnerable and like
shedding like literally there's a moment
where i was just like
naked and she's just like stroking my
hair and i'm just like bawling
it was like this crazy healing moment
that's that moment man
that's that so shoes i mean she's yeah
she brought me back to life in so many
ways but um
yeah so i had like that defining moment
essentially my spirituality like
there was nothing like that there for me
like i always had this like savage like
you can do it like
you can learn anything you have you can
but there wasn't ever this like
like the spirituality that awoken me was
not something that i
got back from childhood it's a new it's
something new that i had never felt
before on this
i can definitely relate to that i can
definitely relate to that and i'm so
grateful for anybody that's listening
that i have
had the opportunity to look into that
side
you know because i feel like you can
only get so fulfilled from the other end
of the spectrum
and i can tell talking to you especially
about that story and thank you for
sharing that that's very personal stuff
and it means a lot that you're able to
come on here and be
vulnerable and yeah i feel like i feel
like i got it oh yeah yeah and a lot of
people have felt like that
you know what i mean and so the fact
that
we're able to have a moment
that is so painful and hurts so much
but i can relate because like the crying
thing i used to like i'm such an
emotional guy bro
such an emotional guy would you hide
crying though like
i would in public you know what i'd even
do like i would like
just avoid the situation completely
because i knew that crying would be a
symptom of it right right you know so
like that would be the thing but
now like not only do i cry about like
happy moments
but like when i'm sad and i gotta let
something out like you gotta let that
[__] out
and whether that's you walking into a
field and screaming at the top of your
lungs
or you sitting by yourself and crying
i urge you yes to literally especially
for
men yeah bro because we feel like we are
not allowed
at all no not at all and like it
definitely i think brings
anger holding that stuff in you know
like for sure i just know that i'm in
such a more peaceful spot
and like less spiteful did you did you
have a moment
like um you want to talk about that what
was your moment what was it like
what led up to this too like what was
your life like i've had many moments so
i've always struggled with addiction
my whole entire life um and i
always was missing something
i didn't know what it was but uh you
know
the other things that made people happy
didn't make me happy
and i always wondered why like you know
how sometimes when like a group of your
friends would be like oh we're like
going to this game and then like you're
like okay and you go to the game but at
the game the whole time you're just
thinking about like
leaving and doing something that's
really you know you're watching them
have fun
exactly exactly and so for me like i
could be in a room full of people and
still feel alone
and like it didn't matter no
you know significance as far as the
things that i was getting or anything
like that
made any difference so like we were
talking about before
i want a solution and my solution was
drugs
you know and because when i put them in
my body i didn't have to feel those raw
real emotions
well and how do you get good at a social
situation you put a little lubricant in
it you put a little alcohol
booze whatever exactly exactly and then
you start to feel okay and you hang on
to that feeling so you're like okay i
can just feel
okay any time i want it's it's a store
away you know or
the dope man's house away or whatever
the case may be it's all the same thing
so i had many breakdown moments i've
been to residential rehab
you know and then i've gotten out and
made the same mistakes
you know and so this last time around
though
and just growing up and
i've had a ton of those breakdown
moments
but what's helped me now
is literally trying to have an ego
death because i feel like my using
was always out of ego
bro for you to like head on say like i
need to have ego death like that's
savage that's
i mean it's a it's a painful confusing
like
damn especially for men yeah because
you publicly too yeah yeah yeah exactly
i mean
in like and what i mean
by it was based off egos my using is
you're self-absorbed literally
when i'm in addiction i'm only thinking
about making
myself feel better how self-absorbed can
you [__] get
right you know what i mean and when
nowadays when i wake up
and i get a workout and i get to go to
work and i get to make sure our
situation's handled and when my mom is
having
a breakdown i get to be there for her
that's what i'm high off of epic yeah
you know like
that's the [__] where it's a real
feeling
and it's not one that you can buy
yeah it's not from an external source
yeah it's something that like only
only you being meticulous and um
present in your own life can bring and i
really want to share this too
because okay so this is how the last
three years looked for me jake
okay yeah lay down three years ago
i got sober for real for real i got on
an airplane
mind you i was in my career excelling
very very well in my career okay uh
but using heavily everything
anything okay numbing it out yeah
numbing it out i made the decision
to get on a plane one morning leave my
career that i had spent years building
and fly to my sister's house where she
was at at the time in san francisco
and detox on a couch okay
and good for you man you know and i'd
already been to
residential so i'm like you know what i
know what i need to do i just need it i
just need to do it you know because like
i've never felt like i didn't know what
i needed to do i always just chose to do
differently
and so i go to my sister's house and you
know i stay there for like 30 days and
i'm talking to my boss and [__] and he's
like
luckily and of course when you're
selling a lot for a company
they're going to take you back no matter
what you know what i mean kind of thing
but yeah but also
they were there for me you know they
knew what i was going through and stuff
like that so
i came back long long story short i came
back i had a lot of people telling me
you need to not go back to this career
it's very stressful
i think it's a big part of the reason
we're using i contacted many people that
i respect to get their opinions
and uh i decided to go back to the job
because i also know something that i
want in my life and i'm not afraid to
say it is massive financial stability
because i understand what that can do
for me and my family
and that's something i've always been
attracted to
now it's not my god before it was
you know so i'm able to see differently
through that but
so long long story short i stay sober
for two years in a couple months right
and
then me and jc uh
we're at our house one night and i'm
having like teeth problems
teeth problems right my [__] teeth
are hurting okay and i'm not being able
to like shut my mouth because i've like
gotten some work done on my teeth right
and i'm feeling like
i can't believe i'm even telling you all
[__] but hey we can edit this out if you
don't want to no
no no no i keep it i like it so
i'm having like teeth problems and i had
been sober for like two years and
four months and my life looks great bro
we just bought a new house
we just got engaged you know
everything's going well and now i'm not
a salesman i'm a sales manager i got
more freedom
i got time on my hands but in that
moment i'm like
i deserve something i deserve something
so i'm like
babe and jc is a [__] writer you know
she knows that drugs and substances
aren't good for me if i want to do
something
she's going to let me do something even
if she doesn't support it
right you know what i mean so we hop in
the car
and drive to the weed store okay i
hadn't smoked weed
in forever and i'm gonna be real honest
i've never been this honest about
something but
we go back to the house and i'm thinking
[__] yeah i'm gonna get a smoke this
weed
and i'm gonna feel better bro i smoke
the weed and start having like a [__]
panic attack
because i haven't smoked in so long but
where i'm going with this
is for because now i've been clean and
sober again completely with no alcohol
no weed for like two months but where
i'm going with this is
after i smoked that weed that night
something happened where
little by little okay then i started
then i told jc i was like all right i'm
just gonna smoke
like every night i don't do it at work
so it's good
you know so i was smoking every night
and then
we went to italy right we went to italy
and then of course i'm flying overseas
so i don't have weed on me
and i'm compulsive and an addict so i'm
like all right
i think i should drink jc oh [__] okay
you know and so
i drink in italy and then i go home and
then i look back and i'm like geez man
it's been like four months since i
decided to do this and i've drank like
120 out of 120 days like this is not
not good right so that thing pulled me
in again didn't it
exactly and where i was going with this
is your question you said did you have a
breakdown
and so i did and it was such a [__]
blessing man because i got to
realize that that just isn't for me
you know and if i am doing it
it's just i take away my god shots i
feel like
you know it's kind of this weird thing
where i put myself in a position to
where i miss a lot of things that i see
when i'm sober
you know yeah so it was kind of like one
of those things
and now these past couple of months like
it was just kind of crazy like
covet happened and i had the opportunity
to start doing music and i started
looking at my job differently that
allowed me to not have such
bad feelings around it because like i
knew what
purpose it was serving right you know
and so that was kind of like
my in the shower moment you know and i
cried and i told jc i was like you do
not deserve
this you know cause like it you know how
it is like maintenance [__] like i
i go hard bro like i go hard so like if
i'm drinking or something like it's
is there's gonna be some throw up some
[__] you know some nights where i
just pass out on the couch like we'd go
to see we went to see uncut
gems a movie with adam sandler all right
and
i go in the mood theorem passed out 30
minutes later you know just from smoking
a drink yeah so
are you going to enjoy the movie are you
going to like try to find a place to get
[__] up at
exactly and it's like at a certain point
it just for me
i know it's not what i'm supposed to be
doing it's not what my purpose calls for
right just feels right yeah it just
feels right to be sober like it feels
like
i'm my true being oh yeah man yeah i
think that's beautiful
i think it's uh it's so cool of you to
talk about it on a podcast too because
it's such
a a weird thing like what's so
uncomfortable
it's like like with me when i talk about
it i'm like dude like
you know i'm i know that i'm supposed to
be doing these things but there's also
this part me that i'm like well like i
also have to like work
like i have to like like do like people
don't want to like hire a dj that they
know did these things yeah i mean like
yeah and it's it's but it's i think
what's more important
than me being able to put on a perfect
shirt and tie and
make that appearance so i can get
corporate gigs i think what's more
important
is helping [__] out in the
music and creative world who are killing
themselves
so you know like the fact that you see
that means everything yeah i gotta do it
means
everything man and it's so true and
guess what
if you can't be truthful in your
environment maybe it's the wrong
environment
yeah you know that's what i ask myself
because i have those same thoughts
especially in such a public thing like
sales
yeah you know and then to switch
directions and like even when i made my
music page
i had the owner of my dealership's
daughter
follow it and you hear yeah
what's in my stuff so of course my first
thought is like oh [__]
you know oh that's so that we do we get
so boxed in with that stuff
yeah this reminds me this is a good um
when it comes to like making like a
music page or like an artist page like i
have a friend who is
like she's been doing fitness forever
and she like doesn't feel like she's
like
the most perfect trained personal
trainer like she doesn't have like that
look as all the other girls
um so she feels like she doesn't want to
post as much on this like
she has a side page an instagram page um
that she wants to be motivational like
like hey i ran
these sets of stairs like hey i had some
struggle with my you know i hadn't
argued with myself about my diet this
morning
um i won though i ate this instead you
know those sort of things
yeah like just being real with people
and motivating people on where she's at
and stuff but
um she i for exactly what it was but it
was essentially some form of like
real fitness people followed her or
something like that
and so she like all of a sudden feels
like well i don't wanna like i
i don't i don't know [__] compared to
you guys so like then we feel
caged in and boxed in by like what our
image needs to be
like what we're posting like yes like if
you had like
like you're gonna be a lot less afraid
to be creative and just like
put out whatever wherever you're
actually at and whatever your actual
thoughts are if you know this people
aren't going to like try to rip you
apart for it right afterwards or
potentially it's crazy and that's such a
good point because
with people following you like you were
talking about before
they once they tune in then you might
start
doing stuff differently you know and
it's hard it's a hard
line to walk but i feel like you have to
just embody yourself you know and
you have to and it's a muscle to build
right right like i don't feel like all
of a sudden you should just
get your phone up and be like this is
how i feel about this and that and put
it on your instagram story but it but
it's uh
it's saying that one thing that you
didn't want to say but you know it's
true to your core
right once and then it kind of builds it
up for where the next time you're like
i am going to post this even though it's
kind of provocative right
right like i've said it like what are
they going to say now like it's like
yeah
like whatever you have to say is just
about that thing it's you obviously
don't have me figured out
yeah but it's again you know we do get
boxed in again just with
like we can't represent ourselves in any
of these social media [__] like we can't
like
like even if you're like this is my
music page like it still doesn't
represent
your music no like there's you know
you're pushing your music on it
you're sharing your music there but it
doesn't represent you or your music or
this side of you or like
dude we can't we can't summarize a human
being with one
page you can't and so many times i'll
consume content and then i'll
meet somebody and i'll be like okay
you know what i mean like it's it's
different
yeah you know in the best way possible
because guess what
just because you created something this
way doesn't mean that you're bound to it
right you know like i'm i feel like i'm
genuinely a nice guy
you might listen to my track and be
opinionated about a certain type of
thing and be like
the [__] you know what i mean or or
think ego or think you know what i mean
so it's like
no that's how i express myself right you
know i mean that's how i express myself
when i'm in my zone that's how
i feel i am giving you that feeling
not to mention i understand the law of
attraction i'm speaking things into
existence
you know what i mean so it's like the
the
the juice is knowing that
you can be you and the right people
that the universe wants around you this
podcast has shown me that crazy
oh i can imagine i can imagine you've
had so many moments where you're just
like wow
yeah i'm just like bro like
synchronicity i think
like you just like like after the
podcast we take the headphones off and
there's like this moment
where it's always like damn bro like i i
don't know why
of course there's the energy of just two
people vibing of course there's that but
there's also this feeling for me
of like that's you okay yep that's
you're doing that thing you do whatever
that is you're doing it yep
and you are on your purpose yeah it
feels like that
and you're bringing it out of people
hopefully man that's what i want to do
so grateful to be on this podcast and
thanks bro and to share
truth you know yeah and like you are
providing an
opportunity for people to do that and it
is just
amazing yeah bro a place to be human in
a world where we're just
trying to bite-size each other and we're
trying to we're trying to like just
point out each other through to me
social media and just
technology and the way that our world
works now
has got us a little [__] up man it's
like and it'll grab you
and it'll it'll tame your it'll it'll
tease you with your bad wolf you know
but like once you start feeding your
good wolf you can start saying like
okay i can help people in these certain
ways too exactly and
and it's hard right right jake it's hard
yeah
like and we can sit here and talk about
okay you know you need to meditate you
need to
just do it and [__] like that but it's
hard it's hard
jim rohn a very successful entrepreneur
that i've always thought he said
getting rich is easy it's really easy
because the things to get rich are very
easy to do
but they're also very easy not to do
you know damn in
when i hear rich i'm not talking about
just money i'm talking about
relationships i'm talking about
health i'm talking about peace of mind
i'm talking about
being able to walk into a room and not
be crippled
right right by the opinions of others
and i see it on my life on a daily basis
man like a couple nights ago
i had the pizza and the soda and i woke
up and i'm like [__]
i get more and more like that nowadays
yeah and and
but this was the cool thing about it is
i took a step back and i'm like okay
i've been doing so good on eating that
putting something bad in me affected me
this bad
you know so like it was cool to see that
and then i was like okay time to get
back on the right track
cause like guess what there's days when
i wake up and i don't
run or i don't lift or i don't listen to
my motivational tape
or when i come home and i've had a rough
day at work i take it out on my fiance
and then i apologize after yeah you know
and it's like
those are character defects that are
alive and well in me
yeah but those things that
we do talk about help me
greatly to fight those absolutely do you
do you ever i think that a huge thing
that a lot of people
because i used to get caught up in it
too is the
the
give me a sec i lost a train no you're
good
uh oh oh identifying ourselves with
oh uh i'm like losing it in and out
identifying ourselves with that moment
of like so so say you're like i've been
killing my diet for four
weeks in a row this is as long as i've
gone i'm killing it what's up like i've
been going to the gym and then you have
that day
where you're like off like where you
just don't feel it you don't make it to
the gym you feel crappy you eat a whole
bucket ice cream like whatever
a lot of times i think what what happens
and what i would do too um
in the bucket ice cream things huge
overeating was such a huge thing for me
too
yeah just feeling so shitty after ova
eating like it's almost like you want to
feel just the pain of overeating not
even the joy
that's it yeah but it's
so what happens i think is we get caught
right [__] here and we identify
ourselves right here we try to say like
okay this is who i am like i
i fell off that diet like wait hold up
you just did this thing for 30 days and
then you had one day where you [__] up
or two days where you [__] up
and now you failed the whole thing what
are you talking about what are you
talking about yeah so that that spot
right there where we try to identify
ourselves and we try to say this is who
i am i guess
me and our egos like yeah yeah [__] your
pieces of [__]
eat more ice cream [__] like stay in
your cave you're safe in there you can
just do this forever you could do this
forever
and then you got like no ego [__] you
bro exactly like we did it i'm back on
track tomorrow
yeah i'm back and maybe the day after
that i'm gonna fall off again but then
the day after because i know
you gotta it's again starting with your
why if your why is an alignment of like
i know that i'm not doing this to see
how many days in a row i can do it i'm
not doing it
for these reasons that other people are
saying i'm doing it for
like to see the edge of my health like i
want to really learn about my health
so that's why i'm dieting and i want to
feel my best and yeah i do feel pretty
good so
let's explore more into that like yeah i
had a day i slipped off
but i get to learn more about my body
tomorrow when i feed it better
yes exactly and you get it like see that
doing those right things does make you
feel good yeah and doing those
it does you know and you get it like
enjoy it all yeah i remember
like you had a post one time gosh this
is from so long ago i bet you're gonna
trip out that i remember this i do some
people for some reason people hella
remember my facebook post i'm very
preachy on facebook
bro i don't even remember what platform
it was on but you were talking about
dieting and you said uh
you said sometimes you just gotta work
out so you can eat the pizza
that's what you said and i correlated
that with
a lot of different things than diet you
know
but stop being so hard you don't have to
abstain right if you don't want to and
it goes back to your time with your why
you know but like
don't beat yourself up about it right
you know because like we want to get
better but you got to understand that
sometimes genetically you're different
than other people it's going to take you
longer yeah that's just a fact
you know what i mean like so we put
ourselves in this box
and you know we tee ourselves up and we
say
oh this is what i'm gonna do and i'm
gonna write this down and stuff like
that but like don't let the detour
totally [__] you
you know and like allow yourself
to be human and i feel like that's why
for me like lately in my life
i'm just trying to like show love man
like i wanna
i wanna support people you know and
i want to tell people that they can do
it and then
really like put action behind them and
like show them
you know that like they can because i
don't know even though like i had a
rough upbringing and stuff like i always
had people around me that were like
you got something yeah you know you know
and it took you a little bit for you to
listen to it folia
exactly well and also i like kind of
like that
i i i don't know if i liked it that
might be the wrong word
i became accustomed to people
knowing me the like person who was like
selling dr
you know and like in the party scene and
like kind of like defiant
um you know i became accustomed to that
and so i'm like all right well [__]
people think it's what i am i'm gonna do
it
right you know yeah i feel like with me
it was like i was accustomed to like
trying to be the rebel like i
am the rebel in a lot of ways like i've
always been you know wearing the crazy
[__] since i was i just love that it's
just because i i like
like different stuff than other people
around me is what it is but yeah
a lot of that like i want to make sure
everybody knows that like
don't use the word we around me because
i'm not like you guys like i want to
make sure that's [__] prevalent yeah
and you know that's a beautiful place to
be but it's also a silly place to be
when you don't like you don't need to
put yourself there like you could be
like people in so many ways that's
beautiful too
you can be like them and be so different
yeah bro you know
like that's that's such a good
perspective to have and it
it allows you to not miss other people's
gifts and other people's
perspectives you know and being able to
learn from them because i know like
when i do feel like that it just makes
me really
shut off the outside world you know and
it's okay to be unique yeah
but not be so
this is the only way you should do it
yeah i mean it's it
you know it's so hard to be understood
in the first place like that's what
we're always
i want you to understand me and then
there's also this like you don't
understand
but there's also like uh we can get you
know same thing
like with your homie we get so trapped
in our own heads of like
like sometimes we think that our
problems are like bro nobody thinks the
crazy thoughts i do
like nobody [__] like no bro you
don't know
like that we all think that we all think
like no bro like
like my thoughts are dark my you know
my past you can't nope like we all think
that we're the worst
but you know there's eight billion
[__] people on this planet
and i'll bet you like within 10 of them
they probably had similar feelings
of course yeah and it's it's in the
power thing about that
is like discovering that that's like a
truth
like that's like bro don't strangle
yourself don't
don't don't hold yourself down like that
like let yourself go
like let let yourself
i guess let yourself be
similar to people in in a sense of like
yeah i'm different and i have different
emotions and i have different feelings
and maybe i don't fit in maybe i'm the
rebel maybe i'm like the outcast
um but i'm also human and so
millions and millions of humans have the
same feelings as me because we can alie
alienate ourselves because of our
personality because of our interests
because like we you know we're the punk
rock we're the
with the defier we're that guy
but you don't have to alienate your your
human emotions like i'm the punk rock
guy who's like
out of all these eight billion eight
billion people i'm the one who feels
pain this much
because that's a real lonely place to
put yourself there's people out there
who are like hey bro i
feel pretty similar maybe not the exact
same but it's a very it's a huge relief
when you could talk to other people
meet other people learn about other
people um listen to other people on like
youtube videos and lectures and stuff
who are just like they talk about like
the pain they're going through and
you're like [__] man maybe it's like
i'm going through like kind of similar
pain and they seem to be okay it's like
maybe it is going to be okay
and it brings a sense of not being alone
yeah like and i feel like at the end of
the day
everybody just wants to be validated
yeah
you know in a certain in a certain
circumstance
and that's why like
it's so it's troubling you know
when that's why i love the thing you did
with the sweatshirts too
in the suicide prevention you know it's
cause like
a lot of people just don't know where
the resources are
you know right yeah because we avoid it
we don't talk about it in the real world
that's the thing
exactly like when you say the word
anxiety like you know five years ago
it's like
you you murmur it and then you like what
you get a pamphlet from
your counselor and that's how you know
about it exactly now it's like kids who
are like 16 years old are like
here's what i know about anxiety like
it's a different world we're talking
about it
we're like hey we got feelings as humans
we don't got to deny them we got to
figure them out we got to learn about
them
no in the way that you really
expand in something is by putting
attention on it
you know and like i don't want to wake
up
and see it on a tdn i'd rather you pass
out a sweatshirt that somebody calls the
number two
you know yeah and
those types of things no matter how
big or how small whether it's you seeing
somebody get
[__] on and walking up to them and being
like
you're you're good man i i'm here for
you yeah
you know like don't listen yeah you know
i mean like
that that little moment right there
not only does it do something for them
but it takes me out of myself
and that's an important thing man
service like i'm sure you've stumbled
across this like you like tony robbins
don't you love tony robbins yeah i feel
like there was a moment
where jay said like uh jc was like uh
said compared you to tony rob's like
he's he's my tony round or he's like
gonna be the next 20 rounds something
like that like yeah i was like oh yes
yes um in dude and he he talks about
it seems like something that before i
wouldn't give the time of day but now i
understand i get it he talks about
service he's like go out and like do
your thing figure out your position blah
blah blah and then
serve like the way he says it just rings
in my head serve
got it and it's it's you know
synchronicities happen man like little
stuff starts popping up you know like
when you're helping other people out
like and from a place of like
not saying that you're perfect in that
you're like i know exactly all your
problems and i can i know
how to help you completely but just like
giving people that open space
or serving or helping people out or
giving people a hug
just being human to people hitting a
like
hitting a little like hey i'm nervous to
share this like
i hope you guys enjoy it it's taken me a
while here it is like
hit a like if you really support your
friend man bro and i've been so
persistent on this and it honestly is
crazy you know
and it's funny because some of the
things that we do to help other people
like make me feel so good yeah you know
what i mean like
like in almost like a selfish way
but it's so cool because you can be
there providing for somebody and then it
gives you that like
real sense of fulfillment yeah it's
crazy that that is that
kind of feels selfish almost like i know
i know
damn you society for letting the word
selfish sneak into there because i get
that bro like
i don't want to talk about it though
like yeah yeah yeah but it's like
i want i want to be there
in a part of it like i feel like in high
school i was so shut off to like
being there for people that weren't like
instantly in my clique or
thing and i've always been a very loyal
person you know so like
i felt like oh if you're not with me and
my friends then
[__] you yeah you know like that but
small town mentality i think
that's just something that comes with i
think so too but then i started seeing
jake like in my career like i'd be at
work and i'd see somebody come in to buy
something and it's like
oh you [__] definitely were not how
you should have been to that person
you know yeah and so it's like a full
spectrum thing that's taught me a lot
about life and it's like
i don't want to be that [__] guy and
deep down
i'm not that guy but that's
an ego that's coming into place and
making you think that you're better than
somebody else or that you shouldn't
involve yourself so like i take a lot of
gratitude now
in like going
the extra length to reach out to people
that i may
not have been the best to you know
and like support them and what they're
doing and like
and guess what i love it at the end of
the day like
we gotta do that for us like now i wanna
give with no expectation
i don't want to like your post in hopes
that you like mine yeah
i want to like your post to let you know
that i'm here and i
see you and i know that what you just
put together to
to put out to everybody takes work and i
want to validate
that i'm proud of you for putting that
work in hell yeah man you know
yeah and so like that's where that's the
space that i want to be in
you know and you know what naturally the
world's going to reciprocate it's
it's a law it's just a law you know like
there's no way around it there's certain
things that happen no matter what
and i've been on the horrible side of
that too
yeah you're human after all yeah you're
human bro yeah for sure i'm glad that
you're in such a
positive space um in such like an
empowering space
coming into music like it's so
you know if i think about like
who i'd listen to and like the
when i was younger i got so much
inspiration without even knowing it from
just listening to [__] like a
lot of times like
yeah maybe it's future maybe they're
rapping about some crazy [__] that like
doesn't really relate to my little white
kid life yeah
but like it's it's given me like like
for me
when i can listen to like earth gang if
you know who they are like when they're
just
just practically falling asleep on the
beat with their voice and just
yeah they're just getting there you're
like what you are still like
when you when you do those things in
your lane it gives other people
permission to do them
in their lane so it's like like even if
you were like if you came out and you're
like i'm the most motivational hip-hop
artist that there is like if that was
your thing like that's your thing people
who
don't even really care about the
motivational side of things still could
[__] with your [__]
in in ways that relate to them because
you're doing it you're
you're fully doing the thing that only
you can do you're being
a pink flower can only be a pink flower
so the red flower is like i'm gonna be
the reddest
red flower i can be i love seeing you
pink flower exactly
exactly and that's why i think it's so
important too to not
be the red flower if you're the pink
flower yeah bro
yeah get it straight i mean yeah explore
like what what can the red flower teach
you
what can that blue one like oh [__] that
one mixed purple and blue
that's incredible i know that's not me
that doesn't represent me but like
i can learn from it i can learn about
myself from them learning about them
and appreciate the color no even though
it's not you
that's what it's about anyway music
appreciating the color that was the most
like full circle
that was like so on the outside of the
universe but also write it in something
i don't know if people are going to
follow that part but if they do you're
here with us
yeah exactly i felt it though
i'm glad you're on the same page yeah so
i want to make sure
that so you're starting this music thing
um it's something that you're just
you're putting your soul into
i think it's super awesome the timing
for everything is great i'm glad you hit
me up
um i want to what's what's your
what's your thoughts like like what do
you you know the world is crazy as hell
right now like that's that's no doubt
and so like i don't
don't don't give me like here's what i'm
gonna do next month and this month like
but
where's your head out with this music
thing like what do you what do you want
to accomplish like what what what's it
what's in it for you right now
so my intention with music
further than the fact that i love it is
i know that the best way for me to
channel my voice is through my music
i feel like people's gifts
they come in a sense where part of it
feels
natural right and so for me music
feels natural and all these serious
things that are going on right now in
the world
we're able to be a voice for him
and do it in a way where it's creative
and where people like to listen
you know and like on that first
thing i did the what's poppin remix like
what you know about a household that
resembles a riot
that's one of the lines in there you
know oh timing even that's great
yeah i wrote that before this happened
that's what i'm saying like yeah it just
works out like that
yeah what you know household that when i
was 13 an older kid told me try this
that's the next bar you know ma why is
stepfather acting violent
like these are all real parts of my life
but guess what i put it on the what's
poppin beat and there ain't no space in
it and it sounds hard when you hear it
right so it's that coming together
and being able to speak a truth
and have people go okay and have a good
time do it make it musical
yeah but there's that one kid who's in
the car who's like
i'm not the only person sitting in the
living room why my dad [__] my mom up
yeah yeah you know what i mean so for
him
he's like okay and i got chills just
thinking about like
no doubt dude just hip hop in
in music does that for so many kids man
for so many kids
did it for me yeah that's why i want to
do it when i listen to eminem
i go into a different state mm-hmm
that's what like and i'm so
protective of him i'm so protective of
him
like it's bad bro it's real bad dude i
mean the real ones are
yeah you know what i mean like and
because he brought something he brought
something to me like
that that he was so
connected with his truth and his truth
was so horrible
but he was able to put that out into the
world
you know and like that's what i want and
here's the thing like also
like i don't want to just do that and
that's why like i showed you the what's
poppin but then after i showed you the
big mad
because the big mad it's like we out
here making people mad because we
popping
you know what i mean like and i'll be on
that type of [__] too because sometimes
like outside
i feel like that yeah i wake up and i'm
like we
we out here right you know what i mean
and so like i want to give you
both and what i really want to do is be
able and this is something
that i think about a lot is be able to
put myself in a position
where you ain't got to go to work mom
like that's what i think about you know
or like taylor
you get a be sitting backstage when i
get off stage with
a hundred [__] like i know you would
love to do
she'd be so supportive oh dude she is
amazing like she is one of the biggest
gifts
in my life jake yeah you guys have a
great relationship
i love seeing your guys's relationship
best brother and sister that is
my that is my heart
man like i did an instagram live the
other
night and we did like this freestyle
thing and the turnout for it was amazing
and it was so cool and i was so grateful
for how it turned out but it's like
when i and she was sitting right next to
me you know we're
playing beats we got a bunch of people
over at my house and everybody's
drinking and smoking weed that's one
thing i want to get clear to like i i
threw a little party the other night i
bought all the alcohol and the weed like
i want people to do what they want it's
still still pretty solid like you you're
not like i know where i'm at you guys be
where you need to be
i'm good people are like you want to hit
it people you i'm like no i'm cool man
like
i went through my [__] man like i still
got
yourself i still got a zip in the
cabinet that you guys can mess with from
the mistakes i was
making a couple months ago but it's like
back to what i was saying about taylor
is like when i look over at her
and like i just am like man this is my
person and it makes me want to do better
you know like when i bought my house you
know what was one of my big thoughts
no matter what happens with my sister
she'll have somewhere to go
and she'll be taken care of that's great
you know what i mean and it's like
that's the stuff that i that i get off
on today
was it was it like when you guys were
growing up were you and taylor pretty
tight
like what because how big is your age
difference like
four years it's four years four years
yeah that's that's solid that you guys
were able to like keep a pretty close
close relationship yeah
we like yeah man we were like on the
like she was the
person who was covering my ears and we
were sitting on the stairs listening to
chaos you know what i mean like and then
she's also the person that would like
get pissed and you know [__] you know
like start hitting me with the better
you know
brother and sister exactly so it's like
she's just been there and
it's there's something jake about
pain you know that
creates magical things yeah
you know whether it's art or your music
and uh
we've been through a lot of pain
together yeah and it's and she can
you can be comfortable knowing it and
knowing she's gonna support you with it
but like there's also that like hype up
like it's like
you know i talk about when i work with
musicians there's this
they know what each other's going to
play because they can look at each other
and say
with their eyes like i'm going in to
this and then you're going to you're
going to accept me with that and it's
like yeah okay cool we're doing this
you know what i imagine i don't know but
with you and your big sis it's probably
like a
hey like i'm gonna feel this i'm gonna
go in there i gotta talk about this now
especially with hip-hop right like
like i'm gonna go in here and your
sister's looking at you like alright i
got you like i've been there i know what
you're saying you gotta say it we gotta
do it
yeah imagine something like that and you
know some people need
you need a homie who's like [__] yeah
bro do it or you need like
a sister or sibling or just somebody to
just say like
you got this but with you it's this
super i mean that's incredible i think
that's so awesome man
i'm i'm super grateful and i think you
know something for the viewers too is
it's
like as much as you need that
relationship
like you need that person who says you
can't
too you know like when at least
for me i can only speak myself but like
i love it both because
i want to be driven
and and when people doubt me i get very
driven i'm a very competitive person
you know so like that's why i was great
in sales is because you put me in an
environment with 10 other people
and now we're gonna see through action
who's gonna come out on top
right you know and so i like that end of
the spectrum too
especially when you're the young one too
like it did you deal with that
in sales like where you were on the
lower end of the spectrum so you
felt like you had to maybe work harder
for respect when you're selling when
you're selling cars and stuff
exactly yeah exactly exactly and
coming from a sense too of like
always wanting certain things you know
and always wanting to provide
stuff and then actually finding a legal
way to get there
in my head i'm like there's no way you
can't go 199
on this you know right
because it it gives you that
it gives you that feeling that you can
make something happen
you know and like i just know being
involved in negative ways to make money
and things like that like
there's just no end result to it you
know so once i found something where
it's like okay i can be proud of this
you know but then here also something i
wanted to talk about
there came a point to where i let that
become my full identity
you know and and that what do you mean
that wasn't
fully who i was right like for me
don't get don't get me wrong i love
people i love sales um
i have a buddy who is in insurance
who is not happy not making what he
should
uh took me like four months on golf
courses and [__] to convince him to come
work for us but like
now he works for us and he's got a place
in kalama and like he just got a new
girl and he's happy as hell
and he's thriving and he just got one of
the biggest paychecks he's ever gotten
in like
that [__] to me seeing that all the way
through
i love that but i like music more
okay and you know what my biggest thing
is
is ownership right like
i urge anybody
who's you know currently found a way to
make a good
financial living to take that and
find something you really really because
i really love sales bro i really do
but not as much as i love music right
you know so like i got to take that
money
and put it into my music
and chasing my full dream because for a
second i had the thought of
[__] maybe maybe this is it maybe i just
have the house and i'm the sales manager
and
you know i have a family and and that
thought scares the hell out of me
yeah so when you got to be true to
yourself there and know like
you know because a lot of people would
say like you got it you're doing perfect
you get you have succeeded and you're
great but if it doesn't feel like that
in your heart bro that's where you got
to be able to say like
okay like where do i need to shift some
[__]
you know exactly it's getting caught
living someone else's life you know
like you couldn't have said it better
yeah
it's i mean it but it's so easy to do
man that we're we're kind of built we're
trying
like it's uh alan watts talks about this
this you know in the western world you
grow up as a kid and you're like
here's what you want to do you want to
go the first 12 year
k through 12 you want to you know you
want to graduate high school and that's
what you want to do
come on graduate high school right
afterwards you got to get prepared to go
to college
right after college you got to make sure
you get the house payment and like what
do you put in your 401k
yeah so these it's it's this structure
that's not it's not bad it works
for billions and millions millions of
people but like
if you're living that life and you're
like you know it like at what point in
ninth grade as you're just going through
do you be like gosh what like what am i
walking towards or
what what am i what goals am i chasing
what carrot am i trying to get that's
like right in front of me like is this
even my carrot you know
is it for you yeah is it for me is it
for you you know because it's like just
cause
college work for somebody else you know
doesn't mean it's gonna work for you but
i still went you know why
because i thought it was i was supposed
to do
right but then my feeling while i was
there wasn't correlating you know and
i've always been in tune with my
feelings
you know so like
for the person who's sitting through
class every day
and then going home and
getting [__] up all night just so your
parents can see you
walk four years later
i'm telling you they'll be more happy
they might be
more they might come at you at the time
when you say [__] this i'm gonna go rent
a little apartment with four of my
homies and we're gonna do this
but let me tell you something in 15
years
when you're not a bitter alcoholic
because of what you put yourself through
and sitting in a cubicle
and you're able to look your mom in the
face and tell her that i love you
and i'm okay inside they'll appreciate
it yes
you know and like
i felt like i owed that to myself
you know as far as like and now i've
never
had a better relationship with like my
family and my mother
and like now i get to
do my unorthodox things whether it be
music or going into a different route
than
college and like show
other people that they can you know
i feel like that's what it's about at
the end of the day
yeah i mean and everything we learn gets
us to where we're at too obviously like
like you you've gotten so much from what
you've done like you've really sharpened
your work ethic like all the
you know all the sales books that you've
read are going to
cross right over to everything you know
right now and everything that you know
in in the music world that you're going
to come across like the things that you
learned
are um your tool belt's full you know
so funny you say that because i was
telling jc the other day i was like such
a blessing though that i did go into
this career because it taught me to
shamelessly promote yeah that's a hard
thing to do
it's a hard thing to do you feel weird
about it yeah you know
and that is actually what i want to call
my record label
when that point comes as shameless
promotions i like that yeah that's tight
because
it's just so like me you know what i
mean like and i've
i don't know do you feel like things
have always
uh happened easy for you
as far as uh
as far as maybe
like career in djing and things like
that
um you know kind of yeah yeah i kind of
had like
it almost felt like momentum that just
got going
um i don't know for me i for many many
years i didn't really have a solid
why like i didn't really like honestly
so with djing
like it'd be that same as typical like
people be like oh bro we got to get you
in clubs we got to get you
in blah blah like you could play
festivals and there's always there's
that part in me that's like oh that'd be
so great but like
i couldn't tell you why not and i
couldn't tell you what else i wanted
more
but i was like that's not my thing like
that's not i don't
really care to like be the number one
headliner like i there was this thing
where i was getting a lot of momentum
with it but i wasn't really
and it's so hard to explain i was
reaching goals without really
having them to aim at yeah you were
gradually just
moved because people i think people move
towards you
yeah you know what i mean i think people
move towards you
and they see you in a certain light yeah
you know and a lot of the time too
people can see you in a light that uh
like you just talked about maybe your
intentions are different
you know but they see how capable you
are right and they see
how inspiring you are in your look in
the way that you care about certain
things and they're like okay like
jay could really do this like he could
right yeah well so and that's you know
in
in more recently like with my like
spiritual awakening was finally like
letting myself do it like i had a friend
who like
literally it was through a text and
somehow the text of all the nice things
people say to me that i just
try to just i try not to dissociate and
deflect
um because i i block love it's like a
thing that i have to work on as i don't
let myself feel these compliments that
people give me sometimes
but i had a i had a friend who uh uh
it was right after my birthday speech a
couple years ago i did this birthday
speech essentially saying like i'm not
gonna kill myself and i'm gonna like
literally try to be whatever i'm
i saw it i loved it yeah and and so and
i i pretty much had a friend um who
wasn't there but it was like
essentially she just said um
like i know you're gonna do something
someday i always thought that and it was
like this simple
like i always thought that and then it
was like a oh yeah bro people have been
telling me that
like in their own words every day and i
didn't believe it
and i didn't because i was like well i
don't want that
instead of like looking at like what
[__] do i want how do i want to
like live when i'm on my death bed like
what do i want to say that i have done
and that's like where my image that's
like where my head is like i'm looking
from the end of my life like what do i
need to what i want to make sure i come
across what do i want to make sure i
accomplish
what do i what ground do i want to walk
across while i'm alive
um and i think in in thinking about you
you're asking if it seems like it seems
like
things came easy in a sense
that speech you did was after the shower
moment yes
a couple days after okay yeah i was i oh
man i was like on cloud nine i was like
in
in the middle of a mystical experience
still i feel like you're getting some
relief
yeah it was so great i i had something
in me that i didn't have before
um but i with djing and you can see that
in that video
yeah bro and you can see that in that
video you know that was a super
uncomfortable like i was really
confident to post that because i was
like i don't care
like at all but then like watching it i
was like oh god like it was just so
uncomfortable to watch for me
yeah um yeah it's like that it's like
you know how like when you record
something
and you hear your voice like sometimes
as little as you hear your voice on like
a snapshot something like [__] that's
how i say
right you know it's so funny we do that
[__] to ourselves so like bro that's
just what everybody else hears and they
don't [__] hate you
no and the only person that's thinking
that is you
yeah that's how over critical we are as
human beings our mind can be such a trap
like that and it's insecurity
yeah i i love where you're going keep
going with that yeah
well well so just just with djing
i i i really i wanted to almost remain
in this like spot of like not being
understood i think like i
i almost didn't like when people
understood me but also i'm crying to be
understood right
yeah yeah yeah yeah but uh so for for
djing it started with
a a like a love like i had a moment
where i was on
um i was at the gorge and i was like
sitting on the hill and i was watching
cascade and i was by myself like my
friends were just doing their own thing
it was a cool like i'll see you guys in
a little bit sort of situation
um and i it was this like man i could do
this like i could make people feel like
this it wasn't like
i could be the one on stage that it
wasn't like that for me but it was like
looking around the people not only right
in front of the stage but
i'm i'm so far away from the stage i'm
looking at people right next to me like
the you know the people in front of the
stage who are raging and like they know
every song like they're feeling it but
also like this person who's never heard
this song before and they're just on the
grass experience in their life
they're feeling something right now and
i was like man like i could i could
do something to make people feel like
that so i got into djing then
um and i kept like following that no way
that's how you
that's how you started yeah yeah that
that's how my love for it got in yeah
cool and i um well and then after that
like within a couple months like
synchronicity i met kelly saint onge if
you know who that is yeah
um and like we kicked it off we like
vibed over like bass nectar like
somebody
like who i'd like nobody in town at that
point i didn't have any friends who knew
this kind of music so we were just we
just vibed and then
within a couple days he literally had me
come over to his house to show me the
ropes of like
all right here's the play button here's
the fader like the ropes of djing the
very first
and he he gave me that opportunity kelly
cena that was i'm super grateful for
that but
so rounding out what i was saying
i was like i was aiming at it it wasn't
that it was like
super easy um i don't know
but i feel like i did always want to
give the image that it was super easy
like i feel
to me it felt like i didn't have
anything ever figured out
at all but like there was this image
that i knew was important that i knew
i had to make sure that everybody
thought that i had it figured out and i
think that that is
a lot of born from like
you know fending for myself when i'm
younger it's like you don't you know
you're not going to show the weaknesses
you're not going to
like when i would go check on my resume
at pacsun before i worked there i'd
leave my backpack outside the store like
they know that i that i brought my
backpack and i walked from school and
like i don't have a ride maybe but like
i left my backpack out there because the
image and i go
and i check on the resume that way so
yeah um i don't know it just
and you start to understand that stuff
through survival mechanisms
right you know for sure like you
definitely do so
i i resonate with that a ton when you
say stuff like that uh
or hey mom have you seen our car drop me
off two blocks away
and i'll walk there yeah bro my thing
was uh
what i would do like every night is i
would and they would know i'm lying i'm
sure
i would i would be like oh yeah my
sister's on her way or my my mom's on
her way and it's
9 30 and then once i see my manager pull
out the parking lot then i start walking
the three miles home
yeah like that was my life that's just
what it's and it wasn't like this like
really
sounds sad right but it wasn't it was
it's just that's that's what i got
how do i survive because if i let you
know this about me then i don't feel
strong i don't feel courage
full of courage and i love that we're on
this topic in this exact situation
because what
it does and this is like totally an
analogy metaphor type of thing not
not exactly but what you do by walking
home
and making the lie is you take away the
opportunity to go
i'm gonna walk home and then the other
person working goes
i'm already going that way you want to
ride
and like i don't want the ride though
but i was like i would try to be too
prideful like
yeah i'm good yeah i know me too me too
man and like
you take that
blessing away because you never know
like then that person takes you home and
they see your situation and maybe they
got a different opportunity for you or
just like you never know like i'm
i'm so obsessed now with the
possibility of opportunity right you
know and just gotta be vulnerable to let
that happen too
you do you do and like you gotta take
that ride yeah
i'll take i'll take the right like i'm
gonna swallow my pride and my ego
you know but it's like it's hard too
because i'm sure
doing things like that got you to a
certain place
bro it's how i it's how i killed it like
it's how i was like yeah
i'm chronos bro like it's built me this
tough
armor by doing you know that's that's
how i live my life it's just like don't
let anybody in sort of thing like and
it's like
of course i let shailene but there's
still levels that i didn't even let her
in
exactly so you know what's weird too
jake is i think that uh
i think that as humans we evolve
you know and like i don't know i think
i think that built a certain part of you
it did
you know and like yeah although it's not
what you want to be today like
i'm grateful i can save for
doing things a certain way you know when
i was going to
even though like they may not have been
right like because it's
taught me a lot about myself and like
about what not to be involved in
exactly but i mean just like you were
saying with with like your your
perspective on you and your mom it's the
same thing like
you learn from it by experiencing it
like you don't have to stay in like a
bitter like i wish i had this i wish i
would have done this it's like well
you did this this is what happened this
is how life was handed to you
like now what how does your perspective
work in a forward movement now
exactly exactly it's like my mom she's
been married like
six times you know and like
i could always tell growing up like you
know when people say stuff but they
don't say it
like you know what they're saying but
they don't say anything like i always
kind of felt that like around my mom and
her getting married and like
as i grow up it's like dude my mom wants
to be loved
or doesn't she right like you know what
i mean like
she wants to be loved like everyone else
on this planet and
she keeps trying so what i'm going to
take out of it is that
she ain't giving up you know what i mean
and so like
those are the perspectives that i'm able
to have
through disciplines that i've chosen to
take part in
right you know and so for people that
are listening
because i know a lot of people probably
feel certain types of ways because you
don't want the neighbors thinking you
know
one thing or the other but it's like
they're just people they're just people
they didn't dude
i always say like what'll what'll stop a
conversation is you just remind
everybody
they didn't ask to be born you didn't
either bro yeah like
like we don't remember that [__] but we
were all babies just like what the [__]
is happening
and then all of a sudden we just had the
moment our life gave us momentum and we
we just started running we had all right
we're walking now
walk with it and we never stopped and
said like what's the momentum i got man
and we're all like that and it's okay
yeah and we're all but if you can get to
a point where you can stop you know what
i want to do right now is um we're
getting up here in time
yeah yeah we'll end it here shortly but
i do want to so
let's just like anybody who by whatever
chance they're listening
and they're they're struggling with
their own addict stuff they're
they're you know drinking too much like
you know i've been there
doing blow up in there yeah all that
just into it too much
um and they want they want a way out
um what do they need like
what do they need to hear or maybe like
what what did you need to hear
or what's something that could aid these
people that does it doesn't make them
feel alone and make them feel alienated
and like you're not weird
hey listener if you got some problems oh
you got some addictions bro me too
[__] me too it happens you're human
that's okay but if you want to get out
of it
and you want to like move on to that
thing that you know is in your heart
like
you can [__] you can i love that
i love that and i love that this is
gonna be the finish um
this is my perspective on it okay as an
addict the reason why we use is because
we're uncomfortable with things in our
life okay
so a lot of the times what we see happen
is
you get clean and you realize that
it wasn't the drugs or the alcohol that
it was just your being
so in order to continue on a path of
sobriety and to not
have or at least decrease
the urge you have to work
on yourself in an unwavering manner
and that is going to look different for
a lot of people
but for me what it looked like
is taking a piece of paper
in a pen and getting my character
defects
laid down so i then can take
accountability for those character
defects
and start to work towards fixing them
and maybe it's not a character defects
maybe you were unfortunate and your
parents didn't have enough money to buy
you braces
and your teeth were [__] up and you
felt shitty about it your whole life
so maybe what's gonna give you hope is
if you sit down and say
well if i go to work and i put this
amount of money away for this amount of
time
i can then get braces if that's
something that you want
now like i said before it's going to
look different for people
some person might say i am going to
embrace these teeth
because these are my danny brown the
wrapper exactly because these are my
teeth and this is me people are
different
okay one person might be completely
fulfilled from the new teeth
one person might be completely fulfilled
for the other so you have to
go deep deep down into your core and
like i talked about previously
ego anybody who's using is trying to
change the way that they feel
they feel it's a very self-centered act
it's a very very self-centered act so i
have to step
out of myself and realize how i'm going
to become of service
to others because it takes me
out of the daily thinking of i need to
be okay
right dude when you're able to you that
moment you're talking about you step out
of yourself
and what happens there like i feel like
the word ego
has been just like people just oh i know
what it means like in
okay it means being cocky like like for
people who don't consume it
the word it sucks i mean it's a
complicated thing to describe
but but i think that when you said step
out of yourself to me
try to see maybe if you're in that
position try to see like
when you step out of yourself make sure
you're looking right back at your ego
like you step out of yourself what's
still there like what do you still want
what's your desires like
those desires those addictions those
things like i need this to feel whole
like
no you [__] don't and when you step
over here and you step out of yourself
they can't see my hand gestures but when
you step out of yourself you can look
so i think for me before i got into ego
work and stuff
i before i really conceptualized what it
was it it was
in my head me versus my depression
that's how i started
because i was like that's how i
conceptualized like how do i not
argue with myself and more of like a
like okay i was being mopey how do i
have this like spark of like a jake
that's like hey [__] stop that
be positive no no let's look at this and
you almost like you exit your body for a
second
take a look at yourself and when you
could say um
i'm just emphasizing that spot if you
can separate yourself
this is my ego this is my depression
take a step outside of yourself just
like you said jace i think that's
yeah yeah and look at it and that's
to take a step out and then to be able
to look at that ego
yeah you know it's gonna hurt it's gonna
hurt it's okay bro it's not forever it's
gonna hurt right now and you know what
you can do is you can make amends
like that that's been a very real part
of my life jake yeah like a very very
real
real part of my life is because and and
understand that that's not you that's
that's the [__] you know like and give
yourself and
also for people that are struggling with
addiction give yourself a break man
i don't care i don't care if you're
freaking if you're 55 and you've never
done anything give yourself a break dude
this is the world yeah bro whatever
tension is in your body right now if
you're listening just relax
give yourself a break bro this is hard
and i'm saying this right now i'm the
most balled up [__] ever all the
damn time seriously
all the time because i'm so concerned
about where i'm going what my life looks
like it's like that but like
when my fiance has me go out into a
field and take my shoes and socks off
and i feel even corny saying it bless
her for this thing yeah
let me tell you something and i put my
feet on the ground and i
put this [__] cell phone so far out
of sight that i just don't even want to
touch it
i never feel better yeah i never feel
better
i love that it puts me in a state where
i don't react
yes i'd be able to just be
that's what yeah it's crazy that's a
beautiful spot to set it off bro
i love this um can you drop your ass uh
if people want to check out your music
yes please i just started a new
instagram account it's
at j saltzman that's
j-a-c-e-s-a-l-t-z-m-a-n
no underscores nothing like that just at
j saltzman and then uh
also soundcloud as well it's going to be
the same exact thing
just put the youtube account up as well
so
all those places we're shooting a visual
for the music video
and we're gonna be bringing you guys
more content the instagram live was fun
what we did on the instagram live is
uh for 50 minutes i put instrumentals on
and the people on the instagram live i
had him comment a word
and i'd rap off that word oh that's so
funny and if they stumped me
their name got put in a drawing to win
100 bucks
that's savage that's a good ass idea
yeah so at the end of the night we drew
out a challenge for you too that's fun
as heck
how did you do how'd it feel like it was
sick bro you know what's so tight is
what
when kelly and i uh we first started
playing parties like after we had like
it had been years since i had been djing
yeah but to get better we would do
almost the same thing we'd go to parties
and it'd be like we're not getting paid
so you can [__] up like
uh but we would he would tell me a song
or he would go through my library
without me looking and he'd load it into
the deck and say transition into that
no she would do that same sort of thing
bro challenge yourself like that i love
it it polishes you it gives people a
show and it lets people get involved
you know right and like it's a big thing
and dude that
instagram live did wonders for the
following on there because i'm trying to
build it up like
of course it was crazy and it's just so
cool and i can't wait to bring people
more performances and stuffs like that
and it's just it's a good time and at
the end of it what i did
is i wrote something special for george
floyd
okay great yeah and so i ended it with
like uh
a very serious tone even though
everybody was turning up and we were
having fun and
i said some real stuff that i had
written that was from the heart
and it was a very cool transition from a
good time to a serious one but
it gave people i feel like the full
experience of me and that's what i want
to do is give people the full experience
of me
and allow them to come
and show themselves in the process and
hope that something that i said because
when i was freestyling i tried to be
super honest to
resonate you know exactly or somebody
says oh [__] he didn't do it his whole
life and he wanted to maybe i'm going to
go do that thing
hell yes you know exactly you can do it
yeah all right listener it's been jay
saltzman and i
check him out take care of yourself
drink some water
do some stretches yeah look in the
mirror and say
it's okay man i'm gonna get it figured
out you're gonna be all right
peace out late hey friends hope you're
enjoying the podcast
if you are just share with a friend
that's all i ask take a screen recording
uh grab a quote and text it out to one
of your homies you don't have to share
it on your facebook or on your social
media i don't care just
if you enjoyed it if you got something
from it just tell someone just
let them know maybe it'll help somebody
out um in my world the
junkyardlove.space website it's still
down but uh
i'm working on it i have some friends
who are helping me out i'm trying to
not just do it all on my own because
then it just doesn't get done right so
i have some friends helping me out um
it'll be up
here in a few weeks and on there will be
all of my
music stuff and my dj mixes like my
whole back catalog will be all linked
there
um to my dj mixes since like 2012 or
something
um and it'll have my youtube channel and
like the
the talks that i um give on youtube
and i'm slowly posting more and more of
those and then it'll also have
meditations and guided meditations and
info about meditation that i will just
compile all the stuff that i do
onto the junkyard loved our space so
that'll be up in a few weeks uh in the
meantime you can find
find me dj stuff jacob from the internet
on mixcloud hope you guys are loving
and living and enjoying your life take
care of yourselves
you